Guide to the Dwight Macdonald Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1864, 1888, 1912-1978; Series I; 23 linear feet (62 boxes)
  - General
    - Barr, W. H.
      See: box 16, folder 418
    - Barrett, William, 1945, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 124)
      See also: box 28, folder 721
    - Barson, Alfred, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 125)
    - Barta, Roland, 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Barzun, Jacques, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Baskin, Leonard, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Batchelor, Clarence D., 1946, 1948, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - Bauer-Mengelberg, Stefan, 1955, 1962, 1972, 1974, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - [Baum?], Werner, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Bazelon, David T.(*), 1944, 1947-1949, 1959, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Bea - Ben (Box 7, Folder 132)
    - Beach, Sylvia, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Beauvoir, Simone de, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - Beck, Julian, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Behrman, S. N.
      See: box 72-73, folder 73-84 box 86, folder 292
    - Beichman, Arnold, 1947-1948, 1953, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Bell, Charles C., 1948 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Bell, Daniel(*), 1944-1948, 1952-1953, 1958, 1961, 1963-1965, 1971-1972, undated (Box 7, Folder 138)
      See also: box 145-146, folder 80-82
    - Bellow, Saul, 1951, undated (Box 7, Folder 139)
      See also: box 48, folder 1171 box 96, folder 397
    - Bendiner, Robert, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 140)
      See also: box 35, folder 902
    - Bendix, Reinhard
    - Bennett, Clif(*), 1947-1948, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 141)
      See also: box 66-68, folder 39-45
    - Bentley, Eric, 1962, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Benton, William, 1928, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Ber - Bes (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - Bergin, Thomas G., 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - Berkeley, Edmund C., 1926-1927 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - Berle, Adolf A., Jr.
      See: box 14, folder 358
    - Berlin, Isaiah, 1957-1960 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Bermel, Albert, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Bernard, L.L., 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Berryman, Eileen (Mrs. John), 1947-1948, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - Berryman, John, 1945, 1947-1951, 1953, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 150)
      See also: box 86, folder 289-291
    - Bettelheim, Bruno(*), 1944-1950, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 151)
      See also: box 5, folder 69 box 16, folder 394
    - Beye, Helen, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - Bhavan, R., 1948, 1950, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Bi - B1 (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - Biafra (American Committee to Keep Biafra Alive), 1968-1969, undated (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - Biddle, Francis, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 156)
      See also: box 16, folder 418 box 9, folder 212
    - Biederman, Charles(*), 1936-1937, 1948, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 157)
    - Biemiller, Ruth, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 158)
    - Bingham, Alfred
      See: box 12, folder 272 box 36, folder 903
    - Bingham, Hiram, Jr., 1940 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - Birnbaum, Norman, 1951, 1956, 1959, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 160)
      See also: box 15, folder 376
    - Bisdorf, Rita, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 161)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1942, 1945, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 162)
    - Blackmur, R. P.
      See: box 143, folder54
    - Black Panther Party
      See: box 269, folder 269
    - Blake, Peter, 1947-1949, 1953, 1963, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 163)
    - Blaustein, Jacob
      See: box 11, folder 265
    - Blish, James, 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 164)
    - Bliven, Bruce
      See: box 36, folder 923 box 42, folder 1030
    - Blach, Madi, 1950, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - Bloch, Helene, 1946, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Block, Herbert L., 1972 (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - Bloomstein, Charles, 1945-1946, 1948-1949, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 168)
    - Blucher, Heinrich, 1960, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 169)
      See also: box 6, folder 98
    - Bly, Robert, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - Bn - Bo (Box 8, Folder 171)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc., 1960, 1967, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - Bogan, Louise, 1943, 1951, 1957-1958, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 173)
      See also: box 136, folder 763
    - Bogdanovich, Peter, 1960-1961, 1965, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - Bohlen, Charles, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - Book Week, 1965, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - Book World, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - Boorstin, Daniel(*), 1949, 1958-1959, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 178)
      See also: box 36, folder 931
    - Borges, Jorge Luis, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Boston University Press, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Bottomore, Thomas
      See: box 26, folder 691 box 51, folder 1261
    - Bowles, Sherman
      See: box 147, folder 1148-1149 box 104-139, folder 476-792
    - Boyden, Polly(*), 1944-1946, 1948, [1952?]-1953, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - Br (Box 9, Folder 183)
    - Bradbury, Ray, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 184)
    - Brandeis, Louis D., 1936 (Box 9, Folder 185)
    - Braude, Michael, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 186)
      See also: box 23, folder 582 box 36, folder 930
    - Braybrooke, Neville, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 187)
    - Break with Conscription Committee
      See: box 23, folder 585
    - Breit, Harvey, 1961, 1963, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 188)
      See also: box 27, folder 715
    - Brenner, Anita
    - Breslow, Paul, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 189)
    - Commission pour la Vérité sur les Crimes de Staline, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 190)
      See also: box 27, folder 715 box 43, folder 1060
    - Breton, Guy, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 191)
    - Bridgetts, Joseph, 1923, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 192)
    - Brite, Mary D., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 193)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation
      See: box 25, folder 642
    - British Film Institute
      See: box 48, folder 1162
    - Broadwater, Bowden, 1948, 1952-[1953?], 1959, 1960, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 194)
    - Brode, Anthony
      See: box 72-73, folder 73-84
    - Brodsky, Joseph
      See: box 15, folder 378
    - Bromley, Dorothy Dunbar, 1939, 1954, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 195)
      See also: box 9, folder 211 box 13, folder 332 box 16, folder 406
    - Brooks, Louise, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 196)
    - Broughton, Shirley
      See: box 51, folder 1260
    - Brown, Fearon
      See: box 10, folder 245
    - Brown, Francis
      See: box 36, folder 932
    - Brown, Norman O., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 197)
    - Brumm, Dorothy, 1944, 1946, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 198)
    - [Brussel, Clara?], 1945 (Box 9, Folder 199)
    - Brustein, Robert, 1960, 1962, 1966, 1968, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 200)
    - Bu - [B-?] (Box 9, Folder 201)
    - Buckley, William F., Jr.(*), 1952-1953, 1956, 1960 [1962?], 1964, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 202)
      See also: box 25, folder 639
    - Burnham, James, 1937, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 203)
      See also: box 34, folder 859
    - Business Week, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 205)
    - Ca - Ch (Box 9, Folder 206)
    - Caffi, Andrea, 1945, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 207)
    - Caillois, Roger
      See: box 13, folder 338 box 27, folder 710
    - Caldecott, Oliver(*), 1947-1948, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 208)
    - Calhoun, Don(*), 1944-1949 (Box 9, Folder 209)
    - Calhoun, Lorraine (Mrs. Don), 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 209)
    - Calkins, Robert D., 1955 (Box 9, Folder 210)
    - Camacho Letter (general)(*), 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 211)
    - Camacho Letter (Victor Serge), 1942 (Box 9, Folder 212)
    - Camacho Letter (general)(*), 1944, undated (Box 9, Folder 213)
    - Camus, Albert, 1946-1948, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 214)
    - Canaday, John, 1961-1962, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 215)
    - The Canadian Forum, 1940, 1945, 1954, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 216)
    - Canadian Literature, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 217)
    - Canby, Henry S., 1923 (Box 10, Folder 218)
    - Cannes Film Festival, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 219)
    - Cannon, James P., 1938, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - Cantine, Holley, 1943, 1945, 1948, 1953, 1964, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 221)
    - Cantine, Jo, [1949?], 1961 (Box 10, Folder 222)
    - Cantor, Milton, 1971-1973, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - Carleton Miscellany
      See: box 60, folder 1402
    - Carmichael, Isabel, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 224)
    - Carmichael, Joel, 1943, 1954-1956, 1967-1970, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 225)
    - Carr, Gladys J.
      See: box 41, folder 1012 box 135-138, folder 753-777
    - Carruth, Hayden, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 226)
    - Carter, John W., 1959, 1965, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, [1947?] (Box 10, Folder 228)
    - Carver, Catharine, 1947-1949, 1951, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 229)
      See also: box 21, folder 525 box 56, folder 1354
    - Casa Editrice Valentino Bompiani & C., 1963-1964, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 230)
    - Casals, Pablo
      See: box 50, folder 1198-1202
    - Cate, Curtis
    - The Catholic Worker
      See: box 13, folder 318
    - Cayton, Horace R., 1944 (Box 10, Folder 231)
    - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions
      See: box 17, folder 431
    - Cerf, Bennett, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 232)
    - Chamberlain, John, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 233)
    - Chapin, Schuyler G., 1964 (Box 10, Folder 234)
    - Chase, Edward T.(*), 1954, 1958, [1962?]-1963, 1965, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 235)
      See also: box 12, folder 299
    - Chase, Richard, 1944, 1946, 1949, 1958, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 236)
    - Chavez, Cesar E., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - Chayefsky, Paddy, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 238)
    - Chermayeff, Serge, 1947-1948, 1958, 1970, undated (Box 10, Folder 239)
    - Chiaromonte, Miriam (Mrs. Nicola)(*), 1944-1945, 1947-1948, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 240)
      See also box 10, folder 241 box 48, folder 1164
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola(*), 1946-1948, undated (Box 10, Folder 241)
      See also: box 10, folder 240 box 17, folder 28 box 48, folder 1164
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola(*), 1949-1953, 1955-1956, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 242)
      See also: box 10, folder 240 box 17, folder 28 box 15, folder 376
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola(*), 1960-1964 (Box 10, Folder 243)
      See also: box 15, folder 376 box 10, folder 240
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola(*), 1965-1972 (Box 10, Folder 244)
      See also: box 10, folder 240
    - The Chimera, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - Chisholm, Shirley
      See: box 55, folder 340
    - Chomsky, Noam, 1963, 1968, 1970, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Ci - Col (Box 11, Folder 247)
    - Ciliga, Anton(*), 1945-1950, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 248)
    - City Life, undated (Box 11, Folder 249)
    - Civil Defense Protest Committee
      See: box 55, folder 1337-1338
    - Civilian Public Service(*), 1943-1948 (Box 11, Folder 250)
      See also: box 5, folder 66 box 6, folder 92 box 7, folder 119 box 7, folder130 box 7, folder 137 box 8, folder 168 box 9, folder 199 box 9, folder 209 box 11, folder 258 box 12, folder 280 box 13, folder 335 box 19, folder 466 box 22, folder 567 box 23, folder 585 box 25, folder 661 box 27, folder 708 box 28, folder 726 box 32, folder 807 box 36, folder 908 box 36, folder 910 box 38, folder 958 box 39, folder 983 box 42, folder 1051 box 55, folder 1331 box 55, folder 1337-1338 box 60, folder 1414 box 135-138, folder 753-777
    - Clark, Eleanor, 1947, undated (Box 11, Folder 251)
    - Clark, Grenville, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 252)
    - Cleaver, Eldridge, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 253)
      See also: box 23, folder 607
    - Clement, Travers, 1945, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 254)
      See also box 27, folder 715
    - Clough, Gordon(*), 1946-1947, 1949-1952, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 255)
    - Coates, Robert M.
      See: box 137, folder 776
    - Coffin, William Sloane, Jr., 1973 (Box 11, Folder 256)
    - Cohen, Elliot E. (Box 11, Folder 256)
    - Cohen, Marshall, 1959, 1962-1963, undated (Box 11, Folder 257)
    - Cole, George, 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 258)
    - Colebrook, Jay, 1950, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 259)
    - Colebrook, Joan(*), 1945, 1947-1949, 1951-1952-[1956?]-1957, 1959-1964, undated (Box 11, Folder 260)
    - Colebrook, Joan(*), 1965-1975 (Box 11, Folder 261)
      See also: box 19, folder 475
    - Collier Books, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 262)
    - Columbia University Forum
      See: box 16, folder 421 box 56, folder 1360
    - Com - Con (Box 11, Folder 263)
    - Comfort, Alexander, 1945-1947, undated (Box 11, Folder 264)
      See also: box 38, folder 958
    - Commentary (*), 1948-1950, 1957-1960, 1962, 1964-1965, 1970, 1975, undated (Box 11, Folder 265)
      See also: box 7, folder 138 box 13, folder 336 box 19, folder 477 box 20, folder 494 box 20, folder 496 box 23, folder 586 box 26, folder 691 box 31, folder 779-780 box 40, folder 998
    - Commission de Relations Internationales Anarchistes
      See: box 108, folder 516
    - Commission on Free Elections in the Dominican Republic
      see: box 52, folder 1262
    - Congrès pour la liberté de la culture, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 266)
    - Committee Against Jimcrow in Military Service and Training
      See: box 61, folder 1431
    - Committee for Amnesty
      See: box 32, folder 807
    - Committee for an Independent Socialist Magazine, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 267)
    - Committee for Democratic Election Laws
      See: box 40, folder 1002
    - Committee for the Advancement of Cultural Freedom in the Soviet Union, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 268)
    - Committee for Non-Violent Revolution
      See: box 26, folder 694
    - Committee to Defend the Panther 21, 1970, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 269)
    - Committee to Free the Five Spanish Sailors, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 270)
    - Committee to Save Salvador Agron
      See: box 13, folder 323
    - Committee to Save the West Village
    - Committee to Secure Justice for Morton Sobell
      See: box 129, folder 704
    - Committee to Stop Nuclear Weapons Tests, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 271)
    - Common Sense, 1936, 1946, [1940s?] (Box 12, Folder 272)
      See also: box 43, folder 1065 box 128, folder 691
    - The Commonweal, 1953, 1971-1972, undated (Box 12, Folder 273)
      See also: box 9, folder 211
    - Conant, James B., 1937 (Box 12, Folder 274)
    - Conference on Non-Violent Revolutionary Socialism
    - Conference on the Status of Soviet Jews, 1967, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 275)
      See also: box, folder 998
    - Delecourt, Andrée (Mrs. Jean), 1950, 1952, 1955-1957, 1962, 1964-1965, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 276)
      See also: box 15, folder 376 box 35, folder 897
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom
      See: box 12, folder 276
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 277)
    - Congress of Racial Equality, 1959-1960, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 278)
      See also: box 16, folder 392; box 23, folder 585; box 39, folder 978; box 61, folder 1431
    - Congresso per la liberta della cultura
    - Connolly, Cyril, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 279)
    - Conscientious objector letters(*), 1944, 1946-1948, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 280)
      See also: box 11, folder 250
    - Constas, Helen(*), [1944?]-1945, 1949-1950, 1954-1956, 1958-1960, 1971, undated (Box 12, Folder 281)
    - Coo - Cz (Box 12, Folder 282)
    - Cooney, James P., 1945-1946 (Box 12, Folder 283)
    - Copeland, Thomas W., 1928-1929, 1937, 1945, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 284)
    - Corey, Lewis, 1936-1937, 1945, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 285)
    - Cork, Jim, 1946, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 286)
      See also: box 21, folder 560
    - Corso, Gregory, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 287)
    - Cort, John
    - Coser, Lewis A., 1940, 1942-1949, 1951-1953, 1955, 1957, 1960-1961, 1963, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 288)
    - Coser, Rose (Mrs. Lewis), 1945 (Box 12, Folder 288)
    - Cosmopolitan, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 289)
    - Council Against Communist Aggression, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 290)
    - Counts, George S., 1944 (Box 12, Folder 291)
      See also: box 5, folder 74 box 16, folder 394 box 34, folder 859
    - Cousins, Norman
      See: box 17, folder 431 box 56, folder 1360
    - Coward-McCann, Inc., 1961, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 292)
    - Cowles Book Company, Inc., 1969 (Box 12, Folder 293)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1947, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 294)
    - Cox, Thomas
      See: box 28, folder 740
    - Cozzens, James Gould, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 295)
    - Cranford, Irving, 1945, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 296)
    - Crawford, Curtis
      See: box 135-138, folder 753-777
    - Crehan, Hub V., [1942?]-1947, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 297)
    - Crist, Judith, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 298)
    - Critic, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 299)
      See also: box 25, folder 650
    - Critique, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 300)
    - Cronin, Morton, 1961, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 301)
    - Crosby, Caresse (Mrs. Harry)
      See: box 105, folder 491
    - Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1957, 1965, 1967-1968, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 302)
    - Crown Publishers, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 303)
    - Cubitt, James, [1957?], 1960, 1962, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 304)
    - Cubitt, Susan (Mrs. James), [1956-1957?], 1958, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 305)
    - Cummings, E. E., 1954 (Box 12, Folder 306)
    - Cunliffe, Marcus, 1960-1961, 1964, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 307)
    - Cunliffe, Mitzi (Mrs. Marcus), 1971, 1973, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 307)
    - Cunningham Press
      See: box 18, folder 448
    - Curti, Merle, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 308)
    - Curwen, Henry Darcy(*), 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 309)
    - Da (Box 13, Folder 310)
    - Daedalus, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 311)
    - Dahl, Robert, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 312)
    - Daily Texan
      See: box 144, folder 65
    - Dale, Ernest, 1954, 1958-1959, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 313)
    - Daniel, Cuthbert, 1948, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 314)
    - Daniel, Yuli
    - Daniels, Jonathan
    - Davids, Arthur
    - Davis, Garry
    - Davis, Jack, 1940, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 315)
    - Davis, Lambert, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 316)
      See also: box 48, folder 1173
    - Davis, Robert Gorham
      See: box 5, folder 574
    - Davison, Peter H., 1959-1960, 1962, 1964, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 317)
    - Day, Dorothy(*), 1952, 1955-[1956?]-1958, 1960, 1962-[1963?]-1965, 1967-1970, undated (Box 13, Folder 318)
      See also: box 8, folder 161
    - De - Di (Box 13, Folder 319)
    - Guérin, Daniel, 1945-1951 (Box 13, Folder 320-321)
      See also: box 60, folder 1409
    - Delecourt, Jean
      See: box 13, folder 320-321
    - Dellinger, David, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 322)
      See also: box 25, folder 646
    - Dembitz, Nanette, 1962, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 323)
    - Deming, Barbara, 1960-[1962-1963?], 1967 (Box 13, Folder 324)
    - Democratic National Convention, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 325)
    - Democrats for Lindsay, Mollen and Costello, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 326)
    - Deren, Eleanora, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 327)
    - Derleth, August, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 328)
    - Dershowitz, Nathan, 1947-1949 (Box 13, Folder 329)
    - DeSilver, Harrison, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 330)
    - DeSilver, Margaret (Mrs. Harrison)(*), 1944-1946, 1948-1949, 1953, 1962, undated (Box 13, Folder 331)
    - Detzer, Dorothy, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 332)
    - Deutsch, Babette, 1948, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 333)
    - Deutsche Blätter, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 334)
    - DeVault, Don, 1944, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 335)
    - Dewey, John, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 336)
      See also box 9, folder 211 box 27, folder 715 box 39, folder 974
    - The Dial Press, 1961, 1966-1967, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 337)
    - Dintzis, Isadore, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 338)
    - Diogène, 1952, 1954-1957, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 338)
      See also: box 27, folder 710
    - Di Prima, Diane
      See: box 16, folder 413
    - Dirlam, Joel, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 339)
      See also: box 25, folder 640
    - Dissent, 1953, 1955, 1958, 1960, undated (Box 13, Folder 339)
      See also: box 12, folder 288 box 15, folder 376 box 18, folder 450
    - Do - Dw (Box 14, Folder 340)
    - Dobell, Byron, 1963-1964, 1966-1969, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 341)
      See also: box 12, folder 276
    - Dodd, Edward H., Jr., 1952 (Box 14, Folder 342)
    - Dorr, Goldthwaite H., 1951 (Box 14, Folder 343)
    - Dos Passos, John, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 344)
      See also: box 9, folder 211 box 27, folder 715
    - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1947, 1950, 1958, 1966, 1972, 1975, undated (Box 14, Folder 345)
      See also: box 15, folder 379
    - Douglas, Paul H., 1948 (Box 14, Folder 346)
    - Draper, Hal, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 347)
    - Drucker, Peter, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 348)
    - The DuBois Centennial, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 349)
    - Duffey, Joseph, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 350)
    - Dugdale, John, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 351)
    - Dugger, Ronnie, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 352)
    - Duncan, Robert, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 353)
    - Dupee, Frederick Wilcox(*), 1927-1928, 1930-1934, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 354)
      See also: box 78, folder 125
    - Dupee, Frederick Wilcox(*), 1938, 1943, 1946, 1950, 1957-1963, 1965-1967, 1971-1973, 1975, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 355)
      See also: box 103, folder 471
    - Ea - El (Box 14, Folder 356)
    - East Hampton Star, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 357)
    - Eastman, Eliena (Mrs. Max), 1956 (Box 14, Folder 358)
    - Eastman, Max(*), 1940, 1945-1946, 1948, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 358)
    - Eastmond, Derek, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 359)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 360)
    - Eddy, George A., 1930, 1937-1938, 1946, 1948-1949, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 361)
    - Edel, Leon, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 362)
    - Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 363)
    - Einbinder, Harvey, 1963-1965, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 364)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1949, 1954, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 365)
      See also: box 16, folder 418
    - Eliot, T.S.(*), 1942-1943, 1948-1949, 1956-1957, 1959-1960, 1962, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 366)
    - Elliott, George P.(*), 1943-1946, 1958, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 367)
    - Ellmann, Richard, 1956, 1959-1961 (Box 15, Folder 368)
    - Elon, Amos, [1960?] (Box 15, Folder 369)
      See also: box 87, folder 305
    - El-Tawil, Alice (Mrs. Bahgat), 1956-[1957?]-1959, 1961, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 370)
    - El-Tawil, Bahgat
      See: box 15, folder 370
    - Em - Ey (Box 15, Folder 371)
    - Embree, John F., 1947 (Box 15, Folder 372)
    - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 373)
    - Emergency Committee for Literary Freedom
      See: box 18, folder 461
    - Emerson, Thomas I., 1951 (Box 15, Folder 374)
    - Encounter, 1955-[1961?]- 1962 (Box 15, Folder 375)
      See also: box 12, folder 276 box 15, folder 376 box 21, folder 550 box 26, folder 691 box 27, folder 706-707 box 50, folder 1205
    - "The Encounter Row", 1958 February-November (Box 15, Folder 376)
    - "The Encounter Row", 1958 December-1959, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 377)
    - Ennis, Bruce
      See: box 128-129, folder 699-701
    - Epstein, Barbara, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 378)
    - Epstein, Jason(*), 1955-1965, 1968, 1972, undated (Box 15, Folder 379)
    - Epstein, Joseph, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 380)
    - Erber, Ernest, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 381)
    - Eros
    - Esquire, 1958-1961, 1963, 1965, 1967-1969, 1971-1972, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 382)
      See also: box 14, folder 341 box 16, folder 399 box 18, folder 460 box 45, folder 1124 box 61, folder 1442
    - Eulau, Heinz, 1944-1945, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 383)
    - Europe-America Groups
    - Evans, Jon, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 384)
    - Evans, Walker, 1937, 1956, 1958, 1962-1963, n.y. (Box 15, Folder 385)
      See also: box 51, folder 1243
    - Evett, Robert
      See: box 36, folder 923
    - Fa - Fi (Box 15, Folder 386)
    - Faber and Faber, Ltd., 1961-1963, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 387)
    - Fabre, Genevieve, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 388)
    - Fact
    - Fairchild, Henry Pratt
    - Famous Writers School, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 389)
    - Fannin, Paul, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 390)
    - Farber, Marjorie (Mrs. Leslie), [1942?], 1946-1949, [1959?] (Box 16, Folder 391)
    - Farmer, James, 1948, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 392)
    - Farrar, Straus and Company, Inc.
      See: box 16, folder 393
    - Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, Inc.
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc., 1947, 1950, 1956, 1964, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 393)